<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on My digital garden</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on My digital garden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://k0ral.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build a gaming PC</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/build-a-gaming-pc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/build-a-gaming-pc/</guid><description>Curated resources Logical Increments PC Part Picker</description></item><item><title>Cookies 🍪</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/cookies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/cookies/</guid><description>Ingrédients pour 1 fournée de ~12 cookies 1 œuf 85g sucre de Cannes 85g beurre salé 150g farine 100g pépites de chocolat 1 sachet de sucre vanillé 1 cuiller à café de levure chimique Procédure Ramollir le beurre Mettre tous les ingrédients dans un bol Malaxer avec les mains jusqu’à ce que le mélange forme une pâte homogène Disposer la pâte par petites boules (~5cm de diamètre), sur un plat à four avec papier sulfurisé Mettre au four pendant 10 minutes à 180°C</description></item><item><title>Install LineageOS on Xiaomi Pocophone F1</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/install-lineageos-on-xiaomi-pocophone-f1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/install-lineageos-on-xiaomi-pocophone-f1/</guid><description>Go to Lineage OS wiki for beryllium, read everything once first, then follow instructions with the following changes:
In section &amp;ldquo;Unlocking the bootloader&amp;rdquo; after enabling developer options, go to Settings &amp;gt; Additional Settings &amp;gt; Developer Options and enable USB Debugging and OEM Unlocking In section &amp;ldquo;Installing LineageOS from recovery&amp;rdquo; before doing anything, download latest firmware (for Android 10) from Xiaomi Firmware Updater before sideloading the LineageOS package, sideload the Xiaomi firmware update</description></item><item><title>Preferred-versions smooth out breaking changes</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/preferred-versions-smooth-out-breaking-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/preferred-versions-smooth-out-breaking-changes/</guid><description>Preferred-versions are a Hackage feature that looks mostly unused, whereas it enables a software release strategy that can mitigate the damage caused by API-breaking changes. This article is an attempt to advertise this strategy.
Note: the idea is applicable to any software ecosystem, provided the concept of preferred-versions is implemented by the installer.
API-breaking changes cause conflicts between:
users who need the changes as soon as possible; users who don’t care about the changes and perceive them as a migration cost only.</description></item><item><title>Printable, comprehensive action cards for Pathfinder 2e</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/printable-comprehensive-action-cards-pathfinder-2e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/printable-comprehensive-action-cards-pathfinder-2e/</guid><description>To whom it may serve, here is a set of printable, comprehensive action cards I&amp;rsquo;ve just designed for Pathfinder 2e. Nothing fancy, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly formatted-text, but still.
Coverage The set includes the following elements from the Core Rulebook:
basic actions (that any character can perform most of the time) specialty basic actions (useful under specific circumstances), except for Activate an Item skill-related actions exploration and downtime activities Actions from Gamemastery Guide and Advanced Player&amp;rsquo;s Guide are not included (for now.</description></item><item><title>Python</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/python/</guid><description>Curated resources The Little Book of Python Anti-Patterns The Hitchhiker’s Guide to Python Curated libraries Functional patterns: functools, itertools, more-itertools Retry strategy: tenacity Test framework: pytest</description></item><item><title>Tabletop role-playing game</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/tabletop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/tabletop/</guid><description>Curated resources Character management
Pathbuilder &amp;ndash; for Pathfinder 2e 5th Edition Spellbook &amp;ndash; spell management for Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons 5e Virtual TableTop
Foundry VTT Maps, assets, tokens, audio
DungeonDraft &amp;ndash; map maker 2-minute Tabletop &amp;ndash; maps, assets &amp;amp; tokens Tabletop audio &amp;ndash; ambient sounds database Databases (rules, items, monsters, lore, &amp;hellip;)
pf2etools.com &amp;ndash; for Pathfinder 2e Archives of Nethys &amp;ndash; for Pathfinder 2e 5e.tools &amp;ndash; for Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons 5e pf2.</description></item><item><title>Uses</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/uses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/uses/</guid><description>Hardware Gaming PC Motherboard: MSI MAG B550 Tomahawk ATX AM4 CPU: AMD Ryzen 5 5600X CPU cooler: be quiet! Pure Rock 2 Video card: Sapphire NITRO+ Radeon RX 6600 XT Memory: Crucial Ballistix 16GB (2x8Go), DDR4-3600 CL16 Power supply: Corsair TX650M Case: Corsair 4000D Airflow Daily driver laptop: Tuxedo Aura 15 Gen 2 (15.6&amp;quot; FHD, AMD Ryzen 5 5500U, 16GB RAM) Monitor: AOC CQ27G2U (27&amp;quot;, 1440p, 144Hz) Headset: SteelSeries Arctis Nova 7 Phone: Xiaomi Pocophone F1, with Lineage OS Desk: Aum World Wave + Handy Office chair: Ikea Markus Software OS: NixOS Display server: sway Terminal: foot Text editor: neovim Browser: librewolf Music player: cmus Video player: mpv Backup: borg Paid services rsync.</description></item><item><title>Video games</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/video-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/notes/video-games/</guid><description>Curated resources SteamPeek &amp;ndash; Steam recommendation engine Grouvee &amp;ndash; video games database RAWG &amp;ndash; video games database My curated list of video games</description></item></channel></rss>