<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on My digital garden</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on My digital garden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://k0ral.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cookies 🍪</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/cookies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/cookies/</guid><description>Ingrédients pour 1 fournée de ~12 cookies 1 œuf 85g sucre de Cannes 85g beurre salé 150g farine 100g pépites de chocolat 1 sachet de sucre vanillé 1 cuiller à café de levure chimique Procédure Ramollir le beurre Mettre tous les ingrédients dans un bol Malaxer avec les mains jusqu’à ce que le mélange forme une pâte homogène Disposer la pâte par petites boules (~5cm de diamètre), sur un plat à four avec papier sulfurisé Mettre au four pendant 10 minutes à 180°C</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="ingrédients-pour-1-fournée-de-12-cookies">Ingrédients pour 1 fournée de ~12 cookies</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 œuf</li>
<li>85g sucre de Cannes</li>
<li>85g beurre salé</li>
<li>150g farine</li>
<li>100g pépites de chocolat</li>
<li>1 sachet de sucre vanillé</li>
<li>1 cuiller à café de levure chimique</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="procédure">Procédure</h2>
<ul>
<li>Ramollir le beurre</li>
<li>Mettre tous les ingrédients dans un bol</li>
<li>Malaxer avec les mains jusqu’à ce que le mélange forme une pâte homogène</li>
<li>Disposer la pâte par petites boules (~5cm de diamètre), sur un plat à four avec papier sulfurisé</li>
<li>Mettre au four pendant 10 minutes à 180°C</li>
</ul>
]]></content></item><item><title>Install LineageOS on Xiaomi Pocophone F1</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/install-lineageos-on-xiaomi-pocophone-f1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/install-lineageos-on-xiaomi-pocophone-f1/</guid><description>Go to Lineage OS wiki for beryllium, read everything once first, then follow instructions with the following changes:
In section &amp;ldquo;Unlocking the bootloader&amp;rdquo; after enabling developer options, go to Settings &amp;gt; Additional Settings &amp;gt; Developer Options and enable USB Debugging and OEM Unlocking In section &amp;ldquo;Installing LineageOS from recovery&amp;rdquo; before doing anything, download latest firmware (for Android 10) from Xiaomi Firmware Updater before sideloading the LineageOS package, sideload the Xiaomi firmware update</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Go to <a href="https://wiki.lineageos.org/devices/beryllium/install">Lineage OS wiki for beryllium</a>, <strong>read everything once</strong> first, then follow instructions with the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>In section &ldquo;Unlocking the bootloader&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>after enabling developer options, go to <code>Settings &gt; Additional Settings &gt; Developer Options</code> and enable <code>USB Debugging</code> and <code>OEM Unlocking</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In section &ldquo;Installing LineageOS from recovery&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>before doing anything, download latest firmware (for Android 10) from <a href="https://xiaomifirmwareupdater.com/firmware/beryllium/">Xiaomi Firmware Updater</a></li>
<li>before sideloading the LineageOS package, sideload the Xiaomi firmware update</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content></item><item><title>Preferred-versions smooth out breaking changes</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/preferred-versions-smooth-out-breaking-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/preferred-versions-smooth-out-breaking-changes/</guid><description>Preferred-versions are a Hackage feature that looks mostly unused, whereas it enables a software release strategy that can mitigate the damage caused by API-breaking changes. This article is an attempt to advertise this strategy.
Note: the idea is applicable to any software ecosystem, provided the concept of preferred-versions is implemented by the installer.
API-breaking changes cause conflicts between:
users who need the changes as soon as possible; users who don’t care about the changes and perceive them as a migration cost only.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Preferred-versions are a <a href="https://hackage.haskell.org/">Hackage</a> feature that looks <a href="https://hackage.haskell.org/packages/preferred">mostly unused</a>, whereas it enables a software release strategy that can mitigate the damage caused by API-breaking changes. This article is an attempt to advertise this strategy.</p>
<p>Note: the idea is applicable to any software ecosystem, provided the concept of preferred-versions is implemented by the installer.</p>
<p>API-breaking changes cause conflicts between:</p>
<ul>
<li>users who need the changes as soon as possible;</li>
<li>users who don’t care about the changes and perceive them as a migration cost only.</li>
</ul>
<p>According to the hackage documentation:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If a range of versions is preferred, it means that the installer won’t install a non-preferred package version unless it is explicitly specified or if it’s the only choice the installer has</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We can leverage this feature to create a transition period during which a new version is available only if explicitly requested in the <code>.cabal</code> file. As a consequence, early-adopters can enjoy the new API while other users aren’t impacted in their daily workflow. In other words: the new API is opt-in.</p>
<p>To be accurate, here is an example procedure:</p>
<ul>
<li>let <code>A.B.C.D</code> be the latest published version (assuming you are following the <a href="https://pvp.haskell.org/">Haskell PVP</a>)</li>
<li>release a new version <code>A.B.C.(D+1)</code> that only includes additional deprecation markers to warn users about the upcoming breaking change;</li>
<li>release a new version <code>A.(B+1).0.0</code> that includes the breaking changes</li>
<li>on Hackage, set the “Preferred versions” such that <code>A.B.C.(D+1)</code> is preferred over <code>A.(B+1).0.0</code></li>
<li>after a reasonable time, remove the preferred version so that <code>A.(B+1).0.0</code> becomes the new default</li>
</ul>
<p>As is often the case, one size does not fit all: this strategy may not be appropriate to your project, but it is worth considering.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Printable, comprehensive action cards for Pathfinder 2e</title><link>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/printable-comprehensive-action-cards-pathfinder-2e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://k0ral.github.io/posts/printable-comprehensive-action-cards-pathfinder-2e/</guid><description>To whom it may serve, here is a set of printable, comprehensive action cards I&amp;rsquo;ve just designed for Pathfinder 2e. Nothing fancy, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly formatted-text, but still.
Coverage The set includes the following elements from the Core Rulebook:
basic actions (that any character can perform most of the time) specialty basic actions (useful under specific circumstances), except for Activate an Item skill-related actions exploration and downtime activities Actions from Gamemastery Guide and Advanced Player&amp;rsquo;s Guide are not included (for now.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To whom it may serve, <a href="/pathfinder2e-action-cards.pdf">here</a> is a set of printable, comprehensive action cards I&rsquo;ve just designed for Pathfinder 2e. Nothing fancy, it&rsquo;s mostly formatted-text, but still.</p>
<h2 id="coverage">Coverage</h2>
<p>The set includes the following elements from the <em>Core Rulebook</em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>basic actions (that any character can perform most of the time)</li>
<li>specialty basic actions (useful under specific circumstances), except for <em>Activate an Item</em></li>
<li>skill-related actions</li>
<li>exploration and downtime activities</li>
</ul>
<p>Actions from <em>Gamemastery Guide</em> and <em>Advanced Player&rsquo;s Guide</em> are not included (for now.)</p>
<h2 id="rationale">Rationale</h2>
<p>My motivation is to selectively distribute such cards to willing players, according to the capabilities of their characters, so that:</p>
<ul>
<li>players are aware of the range of standard actions offered by the ruleset</li>
<li>the effort to check most of the action rules is lowered from &ldquo;browse the rulebook/Archives of Nethys&rdquo; to &ldquo;find and read the relevant card you already have in hand&rdquo;</li>
<li>players are empowered to contribute to the collective effort of obeying the spirit of the rules</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-this-was-made">How this was made</h2>
<p>I made the following design decisions:</p>
<ul>
<li>to allow for more content per card, I picked the Tarot format (70mm x 121mm = 2.75″ x 4.75″), which is bigger than the more traditional Poker format (63mm x 88mm = 2.5″ x 3.5″) while remaining convenient to Manipulate</li>
<li>I had to reword, sometimes even truncate, some rules, to fit in the card format; when significant details were cut, I added a &ldquo;See rulebook&rdquo; mention</li>
<li>as another trick to compress the information, I &ldquo;invented&rdquo; the <em>Trained</em> trait for actions that require the character to be Trained in a specific skill</li>
<li>actions that have short descriptions and are closely-related to each other, are grouped in a single card</li>
<li><em>Activate an Item</em> is excluded because I couldn&rsquo;t find a concise way of describing it, other than just &ldquo;check the item description&rdquo;, which defeats the purpose of making a card</li>
<li>after trying many tools (namely <em>Inkscape</em>, <em>Karbon</em>, <em>Scribus</em>, <em>Python</em> &amp; <em>Cairo</em>, <em>TeX</em>, <em>AbiWord</em>), to my own surprise I settled with <em>LibreOffice Writer</em> to design the cards, because experiments showed that it has the best &ldquo;good-looking / time-consuming&rdquo; ratio, notably because I am Untrained in graphics and also I realized a word-processor makes sense when most of the work involved is text-formatting</li>
<li>my workflow to go from the ODT file to actual cards is:
<ul>
<li>export to PDF from <em>LibreOffice Writer</em> (built-in feature)</li>
<li>convert PDF to 1 image file per page using <em>ImageMagick</em> (you must be <em>Trained</em> in commandline): <code>convert -density 300 -trim cards.pdf -quality 100 card-%03d.jpg</code></li>
<li>upload image files to an online card printer</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>